Today is the last day of school.
It is summer vacation.
Grace is very excited.
This summer will be fun.
Grace is going to visit her grandparents.
They have a cottage.
The cottage is on Lake Erie.
It is a lot of fun.
Grace is going to swim.
She is going to play board games.
She is going to talk with her grandparents.
Grace is going to have fun.
Grace is going to a summer camp.
She will sleep in a cabin.
She will make lots of new friends.
Grace will learn campfire songs.
Camp will be fun.
Grace is going to Cape Cod with her parents.
We are going for two weeks.
We are going to drive.
Grace will see the ocean.
Cape Cod will be beautiful.
Summer vacation is fun.